Guide to the Thomas Ellison Keitt papers, 1758-1945 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library Duke University Durham, N.C., USA
Thomas Ellison Keitt papers 1758-1945 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library, Duke University
Keitt, Thomas Ellison
2.0 Linear Feet Approx. 769 Items
Thomas Ellison Keitt was a resident of Clemson, Oconee County, South Carolina.
Collection comprises papers of the Wadlington, Bauskett, and Keitt familes of Newberry County, South Carolina. Among the papers are records belonging to Thomas Bauskett, a planter, and J. L. Keitt, a farmer, attorney, and state legislator. Documents include legal and financial papers and volumes; personal correspondence; speeches and pamphlets; and genealogical materials. Topics in the correspondence sometimes touch on slave sales and purchases, cotton mills, smallpox, and refer to life in Charleston, South Carolina. There are also Civil War letters of Ellison Summerfield Keitt, captain in the 29th Regiment of S.C. Troops and later the 19th S.C. Cavalry Battalion, including muster rolls of Company M, 20th Regiment. Correspondents include James Wadlington, Thomas Wadlington, John Bauskett, Caroline (Wadlington) Keitt, Thomas W. Keitt, Thomas Ellison Keitt, Laurence Massillon Keitt, Harriet (Sondley) Wadlington, Ann (Bauskett) Wadlington, and William W. Boyce.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. There may be a 48-hour delay in obtaining these materials.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Thomas Ellison Keitt papers were acquired by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library in 1948 and 1969.
Collection Overview
Collection comprises papers of the Wadlington, Bauskett, and Keitt familes of Newberry County, South Carolina. Included are a genealogical chart; social and personal letters with some information on slave sales and purchases, cotton mills, smallpox, and life in Charleston, South Carolina; papers of Thomas Bauskett, a planter, and J.L. Keitt, a farmer, attorney, and state legislator; and Civil War letters of Ellison Summerfield Keitt, captain in the 29th Regiment of S.C. Troops and later the 19th S.C. Cavalry Battalion, including muster rolls of Company M, 20th Regiment. Correspondents include James Wadlington, Thomas Wadlington, John Bauskett, Caroline (Wadlington) Keitt, Thomas W. Keitt, Thomas Ellison Keitt, Laurence Massillon Keitt, Harriet (Sondley) Wadlington, Ann (Bauskett) Wadlington, and William W. Boyce.
Legal papers date from 1770 to 1913, and consist of indentures, wills, deeds, plats, summonses, and records of trial and judgment. Some of these documents concern the work of Thomas Bauskett (an attorney) and James Wadlington (a judge). Other financial papers, 1768-1902, include promissory notes, bills, receipts and small account books of Sarah Cates's children (1819), and Thomas Bauskett (1798). Manuscript volumes include a ledger, 1758-1803, of Thomas Wadlington, Sr.; an inventory of the estate of James Wadlington, 1831-1850; a mercantile account book, 1831-1879, of Ann (Bauskett) Wadlington; and account books, 1931-1939, of Mrs. Thomas Wadlington Keitt, including wages paid agricultural laborers, and subscriptions paid to the Methodist Church at Clemson. There are also miscellaneous speeches, prayers, and writings, and printed material, including pamphlets and clippings related to the Wadlington and Keitt families.
Among the printed materials is a published letter, For Confidential Circulation Among Members of the Secession Party, dated October 24, 1851, which contains information on the Union party and the secession movement in South Carolina. Clippings contain information on Tammany Hall, the Salvation Army, Lord Randolph Churchill, William Booth, Henry George, and H. Clay Bascom.
Subject Headings
These are searchable subject entries for this collection. Performing a search on these subjects in the Duke University Libraries online catalog will bring up other related research materials.
Bauskett family
Keitt family
Waddington family
Confederate States of America. Army. South Carolina Cavalry Regiment, 19th.
Confederate States of America. Army. South Carolina Cavalry Regiment, 20th.
Confederate States of America. Army. South Carolina Cavalry Regiment, 29th.
Agricultural laborers -- South Carolina
Forms (Law) -- South Carolina
Judges -- South Carolina -- Newberry County
Lawyers -- South Carolina -- Newberry County
Methodist Church -- South Carolina
Slaves -- South Carolina
Smallpox -- South Carolina
Charleston (S.C.) -- History
Newberry County (S.C.) -- History
South Carolina -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865
United States -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865
Account books
Ledgers
Muster rolls
Photographs
Related Material
Laurence Massillon Keitt papers
Rubenstein Library, Duke University
Contents of Collection
- Thomas Ellison Keitt papers, 1758-1945 and undated, (4 boxes; 1 oversize folder)
  - Letters, 1817-1907 and undated (Box 1)
  - Legal and financial papers (Box 2)
  - Printed materials, clippings, and other documents (Box 2)
  - Wadlington family records and accounts ledger, 1758-1803 (Box 3)
  - Arithmetic volume, 1788-1822 (Box 3)
  - Inventory of James Wadlington's estate, 1831-1850 (Box 3)
  - Ann Wadlington account book, 1831-1879 (Box 3)
  - Farm account books, 1931-1939 (Box 4)
  - Oversize photographs, 1921-1923 (Opaperfolder 1)
  - Sales deed, 1770 (Opaperfolder 1)
  - Will and testament, 1777 (Opaperfolder 1)
  - Memorandum, 1778 (Opaperfolder 1)